<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[our Mexican adventure]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[our Mexican adventure]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 03:57:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[(6) six Spicy Fingers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>(6) six Spicy Fingers</h1><h2>Learning from the young</h2><p>Its the first Sunday after my family left for Vancouver for a month. I get into the kitchen to make coffee and the all too familiar sight of the tropics stares into my face. A cockroach is sitting on the coffee machine waiving his antennas at me. Initially I get annoyed but then I recognize the opportunity! I am tasked with feeding my sons pets while he is away. This roach will make for a good meal, so I move onto catching it. That bastard is fast but with empty yogurt container at hand and repeatedly moving stuff around as this ‘thing’ keeps hiding, luring some nasty swear words out of me, I caught him. He was dropped into the enclosure containing the two lovebird scorpions. Who is swearing now?</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/095d32fd-97d7-4e2d-951b-8202a92dbec4.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/6-six-spicy-fingers/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5937823c-b2ce-4dae-a69d-b6555a3edf59</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 03:57:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[(4) four Spicy Fingers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>(4) four Spicy Fingers</h1><h2>...impressions of 8 days and 7500 Km</h2><p>Driving through the US verified that stereotypical image of what I always thought road trips in North America would look like, for the most parts anyway. Once we passed Oregon’s snowy mountains, we faced one endless road disappearing into the horizon. The only thing that changed was the vegetation, the scenery and the easily recognizable approach into the next town when signs of Mac Donald and Walmart emerged on the roadside - with some exceptions off course. I am probably exaggerating, but throw the odd ghost town into the mix and the overall impression is pretty much that. The unknown road offered plenty of food for discussions, discoveries and some laughs along with some worries and excitement. A good mix!</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f104bc6f-57ee-4279-a9c6-4a5b271d1c6a.png"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/4-four-spicy-fingers/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5a3ab81c-f9c3-482f-a20c-705a4b283a11</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 23:45:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[(1) Spicy Fingers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>(1) Spicy Fingers</h1><h2>...nope, this is not a cooking site. This is where we write about our Mexican adventures.</h2><p>We first fell in love with Merida on the Yucatan peninsula in early 2015 and over the course of that year decided to live in Mexico for the year to come. We left Roberts Creek in December and drove the 7500km trip down to Mexico in our ‘Snorkel Mobil’ with our 2 kids, 2 dogs and a little trailer in tow. This is our story.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/67df4ef9-10ad-4086-a42f-c12cd0eb3df0.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/1-spicy-fingers/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3df0b1a9-0750-4896-a1fd-510c9b0bf06e</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 21:27:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[(2) two Spicy Fingers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>(2) two Spicy Fingers</h1><h2>Perceptions, Blogs & Social Media</h2><p>We started to plan around investing into some real estate in Mexico end of 2014. Call it retirement planing or midlife crisis, it doesn't really matter. What matters is that our exploration to maybe expand our investment beyond the increasingly unaffordable real-estate market in BC, has evolved into an adventure for the whole family and possibly the most interesting endeavour we have dove into. Naturally we were convinced we’ll write about this trip, always wanted to write a blog. After all, we had many friends who cared to know what we were up to and asked us to share - but till now we never really got there (other than FaceBook posts). I guess we weren’t really sure what we had to say would be something of any value, probably doubted if anyone really cared other than us and some close friends. Both, Jess and I are fairly private in nature and sharing things on a broader scale meant to accept the inevitable comments and criticism on that same larger scale. We have to be at ease with our own writing style and with sharing our views of the world, as we see it, despite some readers possibly judging us for it. We decided we are alright with that. Ergo here we are, after now 5-1/2 months in the Yucatan, we finally decided to start posting.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f95bdda9-dedb-4372-8973-0aebbd297cbd.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/2-two-spicy-fingers/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8e5fcb58-019c-4c4e-9066-965fee5c0545</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 21:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[(3) three Spicy Fingers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>(3) three Spicy Fingers</h1><h2>...crossing over</h2><p>Our first border crossing from Canada into the US was surprisingly more eventful than anticipated. Not that we expected to fly through but after being instructed to park at the customs & immigration area, we had to leave the car keys with 2 officers outside for them to search our vehicle and trailer. Once inside, the officer behind the counter felt our agenda was too out of the norm and was joined by a second officer for them to wrap their heads around what we had laid out as our one year plan. Both officers fired questions at us clearly aimed at investigating wether or not we would somehow disappear in the United States and find work there. They couldn't fathom the fact that we were planning a trip for that length of time and that our destination was Mexico, not the United States. Additionally, that we had no definite route or places planned to stay at on our way down, bypassing the US altogether, really took them for a loop. After repeatedly being asked and telling them our final destination, we then spelled ‘Merida’ out, as well as answered what we did for a living for the border officers to google away and confirm that we didn't make any of this up. By that point, it more likely than not, was out of curiosity. The 2 officers then joined the 2 that had our car keys. All 4 then went through our car and trailer again, before coming back inside with more questions as to why we would expose our children to the dangers of Mexico and have we ever been there before? We said ‘yes, multiple times” before finally, in a friendly manner, asking back; have you been? The answer was “no and as border officers, knowing what we do, we would never consider a trip down”. The conversation now had lost the interrogation factor and became somewhat casual. We were filled in what kind of information patrol officer would receive about Mexico’s border areas. Why what we are doing all seemed so dangerous and irresponsible to them. It all made sense to us from their point of view. Interestingly enough we have European friends who apply the same logic to areas in the US they wouldn't visit after watching the news.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/68968aca-a9e1-404c-aaaf-aa785544775f.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/3-three-spicy-fingers/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4cc6ca53-7218-439d-aec7-a3fd7eeacdb7</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 21:27:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[(5) five Spicy Fingers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>(5) five Spicy Fingers</h1><h2>How safe is Mexico?</h2><p>For some reason mainstream media seems to love picking on Mexico with reports and stories which, if I didn't know any better, would keep me from even considering a trip there. Just like the officers at the US border crossing, most of us would never consider exposing ourselves to the risks of kidnaping and street robbery willingly. Hence, when we shared our plans they were met with some concern. Even now that we have been here for a good while we get comments from people back in Canada and Europe. In conversation with some of these very rational folks we couldn't really hand out the “it just feels right” card, so it helped collecting an inventory of some facts and viewpoints we had gathered throughout our research period and now, while experiencing this wonderful country.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e0b3b34e-d58f-43c4-9061-0a70d235e1fd.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/spicy-fingers/5-five-spicy-fingers/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">070e75f6-b096-4b02-b6f1-239c565b5225</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 21:26:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>